What happened?
You've been in a coma for a whole day.
Is this how the Plague gets treated?
You...
Are you really the Plague?
You have a really sensitive nose,
very much like a friend of mine.
You can even tell the faint smell
of turmeric.
A cheater has to practice for a long time.
By the way,
except for the bedding,
I've packed almost all your luggage.
Take a look
and see if anything is missing.
Nothing's missing—it's all here.
But
why are we packing luggage?
Because we're leaving.
What? W-We are leaving?
Do you think we can still
stay on this ship?
Wait,
it should be you
who can't stay here any longer.
What does it have to do with me?
I am the Sea Plague,
and you are the Plague's cousin.
How many people
do you think will come
seeking revenge on you?
Once you go ashore,
they will torture you
and interrogate you about my whereabouts.
Someone might even cut off
your little friend down there.
I...
I-I am not your cousin!
Do you guys believe him?
-No.
-No, we don't.
I'm really not his cousin!
I don't know this guy!
You... You guys...
What's wrong with you guys?
Aren't you
the knight who protects
Chinese passengers?
Why are they hiding from you
and so afraid of you?
Knight?
There's no knight here.
I am the Plague.
The Plague kills those
with a guilty conscience.
Ordinary people all have things
they feel guilty about.
You are not afraid of me.
You've got no guilt in your heart.
Of course, I have no guilt.
Those with no guilt are
either very kind,
or really evil,
or extremely foolish.
Which type are you?
I...
I-I'm none of them.
Is it that hard not to do anything
against your conscience?
Ask them.
I really don't know how you managed
to grow up being this blunt and honest.
I am an accountant.
An accountant should be firm and clear.
I make a living by being blunt and honest.
If something requires flexibility,
I believe
there will be flexible people
to deal with it.
Now that the job
of accountant has existed
since ancient times,
I believe I can survive.
Chivalry.
Some British value this.
There are some British in Nanyang.
So you will indeed do well there.
But when you arrive in Jinfan,
the people there will probably bury you
under the railway tracks as a foundation.
You are lucky.
You were supposed to die today,
but you didn't.
It means you have really good luck.
Then I must take you with me,
as what I am going to do next today
needs luck.
What do you mean?
Guys.
Good times are always fleeting.
But we will meet again soon.
I will remember every one of your faces.
I will know every bad thing
you say about me
behind my back.
Someone will tell me about
every bad thing you do.
Go back and tell what you saw today
to 10 of your friends.
Otherwise,
you will eventually run into me
someday in the future.
Take the luggage
and go wait for me on the boat I prepared.
See you later.
You...
What are you doing?
You Plague,
why are you so unpredictable?
I'm not a Plague.
I'm your savior.
What savior?
You are just a madman,
a psychopath!
I'm going to Jinfan to find my family.
Where are you kidnapping me to?
Do you think I want to care about you?
Take it and row over there.
No, I'm not going!
You...
Bastards on the Nan'an,
I am back.
Row harder!
Row!
Psychopath.
Almost there.
Wake up, we're almost there.
I haven't asked you
about your name yet.
My name is He Jianxi,
from "When shall we trim
the candle by the west window."
My name is Zhang Hailou,
from "The moon is like a mirror
flying in the sky,
and clouds form a sea mirage."
You can also call me Salty Zhang.
Salty is a homophone
for what Balai people call me.
Is this a crystal palace?
[The Nan'an]
[Archives: The Nanyang Mystery]
[Episode 8]
Where are we?
You even brought wine?
In the Nan'an,
a steamboat
heading for Xiacheng.
Xiacheng?
Why are we going to Xiacheng?
I want to go to Jinfan!
Bro, what on earth are you doing?
I'm saving your life.
You're so stubborn but still alive.
Your ancestors must've accumulated a lot
of merit and saved many people.
My ancestors have accumulated merit?
If they had done it,
I wouldn't have met you!
No way.
I can't go to Xiacheng.
You bastard.
I'm going to Jinfan.
My younger brother is
still waiting for me!
What? Should I throw you overboard now,
so you can swim back?
Listen,
no one would believe
that someone could sneak
onto a ship in these waters.
This ship is very safe,
with neither bad sailors
nor scammers like those guys.
It's much safer than the Bowne.
So don't worry.
After we arrive in Xiacheng,
I will let you go back to Jinfan.
It's just a little detour.
Then tell me the truth.
Who exactly are you?
Who on earth are you?
Who are you?
What are you doing now?
I'm taking you to the dining hall first.
That way.
Let's go!
Where are we going?
Just sit here and wait for me to return.
What if someone comes?
There are a lot of drunks here.
Just pretend to be drunk.
I'm sure no one will notice.
Where are you going?
There are 10 medical staff
on the ship in total,
including 3 doctors
and 7 nurses.
The murderers who spread
the Twilight Grass
are among them.
At this time,
there must be someone
on duty in the clinic.
Find the murderers,
keep one to take back to Nanyang,
and get rid of the rest.
Could the murderer be someone else?
You're Mr. Zhang Ruipu's nephew,
Mr. Zhang Hailou, right?
This wound...
Oh, no.
This powder is made from Twilight Grass.
Who took you to sneak onto the ship?
He brought me on board.
Who are you? What are you doing?
Come over here.
Let me show you some "love."
Plague?
Are you okay?
Cousin,
you really ratted me out.
No.
The patrolmen found me.
I had no other choice...
You did a good job ratting me out.
It doesn't really matter anyway.
After all, I am a legitimate
first-class passenger on this ship.
You are the one without a ticket.
Can he be saved?
He was killed in one blow.
He died without much pain.
Cousin,
you didn't kill anyone,
but they died because of you.
What on earth is going on here?
You said this ship was very safe!
W-What exactly do you do?
I told you, I'll tell you later.
But these people
are robbers.
If you don't let go
of our personal grudges,
the money on this ship will be robbed,
and the women will be abused.
The women won't be abused.
One of them is a woman.
I can smell it.
Like Shrimpie's nose...
But if what you said is true,
and they are robbers,
we should immediately
inform everyone else on the ship.
We might not make it that far.
What are you doing now?
What is this smell?
No,
wait a minute.
Don't go in.
Do you smell that?
The smell coming out of this room
is so weird.
How many people died in there?
Why does it smell so strongly of blood?
Cousin.
Look, this room is actually a trap.
A trap?
What trap?
These assassins must have been prepared
the moment they knew Zhang Ruipu's sailor
was guiding me.
Assassins?
Didn't you just say they were robbers?
If I hadn't been forced
to jump into the sea,
I would have gone
to investigate the clinic
and fallen into their trap,
and I might have been dead now.
Who are you?
But I lucked out
and arrived here nearly half a day late.
This was enough
to make the assassins ambushing here
let their guard down.
Were it not for you...
Were it not for these coincidences,
I would have ended up
just like them right now,
lying dead on the ground.
These bodies...
Were they killed by you
or those robbers?
I thought these doctors
on the ship were the murderers,
but now they are dead.
That means apart from them,
there must be someone else involved
in spreading the toxic weed.
These people are highly skilled
and ruthless fighters.
Or maybe these doctors
were just used by them
and have now been silenced.
Burn all the evidence.
Don't let anyone go!
That sounds like their style.
These are traces of Twilight Grass Poison.
They were killed by Twilight Grass Poison.
The assassins turned the corpses
into traps.
Once triggered,
Twilight Grass Poison will spray
from their mouths.
So this must be
a storage device
for Twilight Grass.
Plague,
I'm begging you.
Can you tell me the truth?
Can I make it to Jinfan alive?
It seems that
the murderers have been digging
into Twilight Grass just like Shrimpie.
Look, Cousin.
This is a toxic weed device
that contains a highly poisonous plant.
Just one small unit like this
is enough to kill 10 adult men.
Using this poison
to kill only you is
indeed overkill.
Not to mention that they've prepared
so much of it.
Are they going to kill everyone
on this ship?
What's wrong with you?
Didn't you tell me
that the Nan'an was safer than the Bowne?
They wouldn't go as far
as killing everyone on the ship.
But one thing for sure is
that they're targeting not just me.
But besides those patients
seeking treatment and me,
who else would come to this clinic?
Could it be anyone
who has traced it to the clinic?
Their real target is anyone
who wants to investigate
Twilight Grass Poison on the Nan'an.
Is that what
the Pitcher Plant Project means?
[N P]
Pitcher...
Cousin,
hide this.
You...
I...
[Sailor Duty Room]
Song Cai. Song Cai.
Song Cai.
Song...
[Sailor Roster of the Nan'an]
[Song Cai] [Zhang Haiyun]
Zhang Haiyun?
There was indeed someone
from the Southern Archives.
[He Yufen] [Du Rusong]
[Liu Yang, Zhang Jie, Li Fengchun]
[Sun Lei, Zhang Siye]
[Li Fengchun]
[328 Li Fengchun]
[Zhao Qiaoke]
[325 Zhao Qiaoke]
[Dong Haishu]
[305 Dong Haishu]
NP refers to pitcher plants.
[N P]
You were warning
the agents boarding the ship
to investigate after you
that the entire Nan'an is
a trap to hunt down
the Southern Archives agents.
Anyone from the Archives
who boards the Nan'an
to investigate the case
will be led by the clues
designed by the assassins
into a trap
and then get killed.
They are all from the Archives.
Are they dead?
Are they all dead?
So,
the murderers deliberately used
the Nan'an to spread Twilight Grass
so as to attract people from the Archives
to board and investigate.
Then what is the Evil God for?
To bewitch and eliminate us?
[305 Dong Haishu]
The agents came from everywhere
and didn't know each other.
Ordinary agents were killed
by the assassins.
Agents who found clues followed them
and fell into the trap,
either being killed
by Twilight Grass Poison
[325 Jo Qiao Ke]
or being wiped out by the Evil God.
[328 Li Fengchun]
It's blood.
So Song Cai used flies
to find bloodstains
and figure out where people died.
Fourteen agents were killed
in first and second class alone.
How many more agents were killed
in third class?
Why would the murderers do this?
Is it revenge for my destruction
of Panhua Reef?
Are those warlords the masterminds?
Did they set up such a complicated trap
to take revenge on an organization?
Wait,
did Zhang Ruipu know this was a trap?
You go to the ship
to help me investigate the case.
So you wanted those assassins
to mistake me for you
and let me die in your place on the ship.
So you never planned
to let me get off the ship
in the first place.
This is bad.
Shrimpie is of no value to Zhang Ruipu.
Would he...
No,
as smart as Shrimpie is,
he wouldn't die so fast.
I'll make the ship turn around
and go back to Xucheng to save Shrimpie.
What are you doing now?
Catching bad guys.
Does this have anything to do
with you throwing the dead bodies?
If someone comes,
can you explain
your relationship with these bodies?
You've got a point.
Cousin, follow me.
Where to now?
To meet
our old rivals.
About the robbers you mentioned before,
are they...
[Go up and down the auxiliary ladders
steadily and slowly.]
You should have drunk less.
This...
You're blotto.
Are those robbers you mentioned
the same guys who killed
the people in the clinic?
The robbers are still hiding
in the third-class cabin.
To uphold justice,
we must expose them.
Wait,
even if you catch them now,
obviously, the ship police are
no match for them.
I think what you should do now is
find and gather more ship police here.
It's too late, Cousin.
They will quickly clean up the evidence
and escape.
We must catch them.
As long as we catch one,
I can just go meet Miss Dong,
take her hostage,
make her turn the ship around,
and hurry back to save Shrimpie.
Let's go.
[Third-Class Cabin]
I still underestimated
Twilight Grass Poison.
I need to figure out a way.
Where on earth did Zhang Hailou go?
As expected of you, the lucky dog.
Get down.
Crouch down.
Turn around.
Turn around!
Catch him.
Three, two, one.
What are you doing?
Now you just walk in.
Don't worry.
Those bad guys won't dare to act rashly.
W-Why?
Because they don't know who you are.
So they will only think
you are provoking them.
They'll observe you in secret.
What about you?
Of course, I will observe
them who are observing you in secret.
Go ahead.
I...
I-I can't do it.
Who is this?
Is this person dead?
It's terrifying.
Why is there blood on this person? Look.
Go find the ship police now.
Hurry up.
Zhang Hailou.
[Bai Zhu, Assassin]
Hi, lady.
Hi.
I'll take you upstairs to have dinner.
Hey, bro.
Maybe you're in the wrong seat.
These two girls are the only ones here
who are not afraid of the dead body.
They didn't flinch at all.
One of them is a woman.
I can smell it.
It must be you two.
I didn't expect to meet
two beautiful ladies like you
in this place.
Seems like these two assassins
got separated from their crew.
Let me catch one
and hurry to find Miss Dong.
Actually, if you eat
too much Chinese food,
having Western food occasionally
for a change of taste
is also a good idea.
Yeah.
-Miss?
-I also think so.
Oh, miss...
I've been looking for you.
I followed you all the way here.
Did you drop a handkerchief?
Look, I picked it up to return it to you.
This isn't mine.
Sir, you're mistaken.
How can it not be yours?
You were the only one
walking along the way here.
Even if it's not yours,
just take it for now.
Thank you, sir.
But I never use this kind
of sandalwood-scented handkerchief.
I'm afraid
I have to decline your kindness.
Why wouldn't you use it?
Don't you have a bloodstain on your dress?
Everyone, see if there's
a bloodstain on her dress.
What happened?
What a pity for this dress.
Bai Zhu, look at you.
I told you to be careful in the kitchen.
How did you still get your dress dirty?
I was careless.
Thank you for reminding me, sir.
Don't mention it.
I just think your dress looks pretty nice.
The bloodstain is fresh.
It's still not too late
to wash it off now, right?
Young Lady,
I have nice washing supplies in my room.
You can go there to clean it up.
I promise you'll get a clean dress back.
I will take her to your room.
Listen,
let me take her to your room...
Well, I'm just worried...
You see, there's a motley crew
in the third-class cabin,
with too many eyes watching.
If anything
goes wrong,
and
Miss Dong finds out later
and starts investigating,
we'll have a hard time explaining it.
Okay?
Bro,
tell me your room number.
I'll take her there.
1509.
Let's go.
Sir,
we are accompanying the foreign gentleman.
It has nothing to do with you, right?
Do you want to get involved, too?
Not exactly.
I'm worried
that your foreign language is too poor,
and the foreign gentleman
wouldn't get a hot meal.
Let's go.
What a pity.
You're going to die young.
Bai Zhu,
since this gentleman wants to pursue you,
just try to get along with him properly.
Sir,
I also have some clothes to wash.
How about I go wash them
in my friend's place?
Alright.
Go.
Sir.
Found her!
I smelled it. It was her!
She was the one who fought you just now!
The scent is exactly the same.
Do you know how awkward you are right now?
Do you know you're going to die?
Fire! It's on fire!
Everyone, evacuate to the deck!
Fire!
Run!
Fire! Fire!
It's on fire!
Run!
Go!
Get out of the way!
Plague!
It's him?
Hailou's friend.
I can't see!
Hold on to me!
Why is it so dark?
The one with the fluorescent mark
on his back is him.
Guys, get him!
There's Twilight Grass Poison
on the blade.
I must finish this quickly.
Who is it?
Sir,
are you okay?
Blood?
Give this money
to Zhang Hailou.
He's the Plague of Nanyang.
Pardon?
What did you say?
Plague.
Plague!